Finding Aid for the Leonard A. Stidley Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Leonard A. Stidley Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0944
1.68 linear_feet
- Homily/Sermon
  - “He that Overcometh”, 1934 January 14 (Box 1)
  - “In a Time of Uncertainty Absalom Went Forth”, 1936 November 1 (Box 1)
  - “Lord I Believe, Help Thaw My Unbelief”, 1936 March 15 (Box 1)
  - “Reign of God”, 1936 December 27 (Box 1)
  - “A Desert Shall Bloom”, 1942 July 12 (Box 1)
  - “Who is My Brother?”, 1935 February 25 (Box 1)
  - “Simplicity in a Complex Age”, 1933 November 19 (Box 1)
  - “The Bible Speaks in Modern Times”, 1936 December 6 (Box 1)
  - Homily and Bulletin for Brotherhood Day, 1934 April 29 (Box 1)
  - “The Resurrection of Jesus and the Eternal Life” Homilies for Eastertide, 1940 April 9-11 (Box 1)
  - “Behold, the Place Where They Laid Him!” Homily for Easter, 1937 March 28, 1937 March 28 (Box 1)
  - “Be Ye Perfect”, 1937 April 4 (Box 1)
  - “The Chameleon”, 1941 April 19 (Box 1)
  - Materials and Homily for Service in Fairfield Chapel, 1937-1940 Circa October 24-27 (Box 1)
  - “Prayer in a Medicine Age”, 1933 January 22 (Box 1)
  - “The Cost of Discipleship”, 1935 April 28 (Box 1)
  - “Behold the Man”, 1936 March 14 (Box 1)
  - Sermon on Church of Jesus Christ, 1937 December 8 (Box 1)
  - Sermon on “Church and Social Service, 1947 May 1 (Box 1)
  - “Two Great Commandments: The Dynamics of Life”, 1937 June 6 (Box 1)
  - “Behold! Behold! Behold!”, 1937 February 21 (Box 1)
  - “Feed My Sheep: Satisfying Basic Hungers”, 1937 April 11 (Box 1)
  - “The Type of Church I’d Like to Join”, 1940 November 20 (Box 1)
  - Series of Homilies on Symbols of Cross, Chi Ro, and Creation, 1940 October 22-25 (Box 1)
  - “From the Vantage Point of Fourteen Years” for Church of All Nations (COAN), 1932 November 6 (Box 1)
  - “What is the Good Life? For COAN, 1935 May 26 (Box 1)
  - “Behold, What Manner of Love This is!” (Box 1)
  - “Does God Guide?”, 1936 October 11 (Box 1)
  - Materials and Homilies for Day of Prayer Chapel Services (Box 1)
  - Two Sermons for Chapel Service, 1937 November 10-11 (Box 1)
  - “How to Get Into the Kingdom”, 1944 May 6 (Box 1)
  - “Teach us to Pray” (Delivered at various events between 1935 and 1948) (Box 1)
  - “Jesus Came Preaching”, 1934 November 4 (Box 1)
  - “Fundamental Questions in a Heroic Day”, 1933 November 5 (Box 1)
  - “Thy Kingdom Come”, 1935 May 5 (Box 1)
  - “Behold the Cross”, and “The Meaning of the Cross”, 1932 February 12, 1950 March 19 (Box 1)
  - “Disappointments of Jesus”, 1932 March 13, 1936 April 26 (Box 1)
  - “One Secret of a Triumphant Life”, 1935 March 3 (Box 1)
  - “Frequencies of Sins”, 1935 March 24 (Box 1)
  - “Increase our Faith”, 1935 April 14 (Box 1)
  - “Finding God in the Depression”, 1932 November 15 (Box 1)
  - “From Death to Life” Easter Message, 1936 April 12, 1943 April 24 (Box 1)
  - “We Have Seen the Star: Jesus as a Picture of God”, 1932 December 18 (Box 1)
  - “All Things Belong to You”, 1933 October 8 (Box 1)
  - “Religion and Change”, 1933 October 1 (Box 1)
  - “Paradoxes of Religion”, 1933 October 15 (Box 1)
  - “Overcoming Fear”, 1933 April 16 (Box 1)
  - “Light from the Darkness of Life” Easter Sunday, 1932 March 27 (Box 1)
  - “Beneath the Shadows of Mystery”, 1932 October 30 (Box 1)
  - “Art Thou He Who Should Come or Do We Look for Another?”, 1932 November 20 (Box 1)
  - “New Buildings of Hope from Old Ruins of Despair”, 1932 February 6 (Box 1)
  - “An Abundant Life”, 1936 March 22 (Box 1)
  - “Meeting a Crisis- The Book of Job”, 1935 October 20 (Box 1)
  - Sermon for Russian Young People’s Easter Service, 1934 April 8 (Box 1)
  - “That They May Be One: Religious Unity and Toleration”, 1934 April 15 (Box 1)
  - “A Young Man and the Future Job”, 1932 November 26, 1934 December 5 (Box 2)
  - “New Years Technocracy”, 1933 January 1 (Box 2)
  - “Behold the Tabernacle of God is with Men”, 1946 January 13, 1946 June 30, 1947 January 5 (Box 2)
  - “Why? Why? The Question of Meaning”, 1937 February 7, 1949 July 24 (Box 2)
  - “I will Lift Mine Eyes Unto the Lord”, 1932 October 2 (Box 2)
  - “A New Temple for a New Year”, 1931 December 27, 1932 January 3 (Box 2)
  - “Seek and Ye Shall Find”, 1936 February 23 (Box 2)
  - “The Scandal of Christianity”, 1929 September 15 (Box 2)
  - “Depression: What do People Need Today?”, 1932 January 23 (Box 2)
  - “Human Nature- A Balanced Equation”, 1932 April 10 (Box 2)
  - “Yet They May Beget, But Will Not I Forget”, 1933 May 14 (Box 2)
  - “Whose Affair is this? A Sermon on Sin”, 1932 October 9 (Box 2)
  - “Salvation in an Age of Science”, 1932 October 16 (Box 2)
  - “On Behalf of the Church…”, 1932 January 23 (Box 2)
  - “An Open Letter to the President: Moses Saw But Never Entered the Promised Land”, 1935 September 13 (Box 2)
  - “Without Sound of Hammer”, 1932 February 7 (Box 2)
  - “Behold, I Make All Things New”, 1933 April 30, 1944 April 9 (Box 2)
  - Sermon, “The Authority of Jesus”, 1935 February 17 (Box 2)
  - “Beyond Conversation”, 1935 January 27 (Box 2)
  - “The Leadership of Jesus: What Does it Mean Today?”, 1935 February 3 (Box 2)
  - Homily/Sermon and Info/Materials, “Who are Christians?” and Report from New York East Conference, 1935 May 19 (Box 2)
  - “A Still Small Voice: Does God Speak Thru the Conscience?”, 1935 January 20 (Box 2)
  - “Fear and Faith”, 1932 April 23 (Box 2)
  - “The Unreality of the Cross”, 1934 December 10 (Box 2)
  - “Not Mine- But Thine Will be Done”, 1936 May 24 (Box 2)
  - Christian Church and the Social Order, 1934 December 2 (Box 2)
  - “Follow Me”, 1936 January 5 (Box 2)
  - “Go Ye Into All the World” Sermon on Missions, 1933 November 26 (Box 2)
  - “A Christian Interpretation of Peace and War”, 1935 April 7 (Box 2)
  - “For the Former Things are Passed Away” Sermon for Armistice Day, 1936 November 8 (Box 2)
  - Homily/Sermon and Materials, Sermon “Peace, Peace, and There is No Peace: The Kingdom of God is Peace” and Materials for Armistice Day Service., 1935 November 10 (Box 2)
  - “The Radicalism of Christ”, 1936 April 19 (Box 2)
  - “A Twofold Gospel”, 1935 January 6 (Box 2)
  - Sermon, “Immortal Life”, for Bowery (NYC, NY) YMCA Easter Breakfast, 1934 April 1 (Box 2)
  - “What I Owe to Christ”, 1933 March 5 (Box 2)
  - “All Things Not Yet Subject to Him”, 1936 April 5 (Box 2)
  - “What Seek Ye?”, 1935 September 6 (Box 2)
  - “Thy Kingdom Come”, 1936 August 16, 1936 February 16 (Box 2)
  - “Suffer Many Things”, 1936 March 29 (Box 2)
  - “Satisfying Man’s Hunger… (Making Life Worthwhile), 1933 April 23 (Box 2)
  - “Lo, I am With You Always”, 1935 June 2 (Box 2)
  - “God- Heaven Need”, 1935 March 17 (Box 2)
  - “God and Security”, 1933 November 12 (Box 2)
  - “Gods of Today”, 1932 April 17 (Box 2)
  - “The Church Today”, 1943 March 9 (Box 2)
  - “The Meaning of Christmas”, 1943 December 12-17 (Box 2)
  - “Recreating Faith”, 1933 March 12 (Box 2)
  - “I am the Way, the Truth, the Life”, 1935 December 8 (Box 2)
  - “Under the Shadow of a Great Rock in a Weary Land”, 1936 November 29 (Box 2)
  - “The Christian Church Today”, 1933 December 3 (Box 2)
  - “Is the Religion of Jesus for Today?”, 1933 March 19 (Box 2)
  - “The Cross… Unless Blood is Spilled There is No Remission of Sins”, 1934 February 18 (Box 2)
  - “The Bible- Spiritual Thirst” Celebrating the 400th Anniversary of the Coverdale Bible Translation, 1935 December 15 (Box 2)
  - “What Crucified Christ?”, 1934 March 11 (Box 2)
  - “I Lay My Life Down for My Friends: Why did Jesus Permit Himself to be Crucified?”, 1934 March 18 (Box 2)
  - “Great Coronations in History”, 1932 March 20 (Box 2)
  - “How Does God Speak to Us? Finding the Will of God”, 1932 November 27 (Box 2)
  - “The Religion of Abraham Lincoln”, 1934 February 11 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln’s Birthday Sermon “Lincoln and Brotherhood”, 1946 February 10 (Box 2)
  - Memorial Day/Heritage Day Sermon, 1943 May 30-1948 May 30 (Box 2)
  - “The Meaning of Christmas”, 1936 December 20 (Box 2)
  - “The Meaning of Christmas”, 1934 December 16 (Box 2)
  - “Arrows of Mystery” Sermon for Palm Sunday, 1935 April 14 (Box 3)
  - “Be Ye Thankful” (Thanksgiving Sermon), 1935 November 24 (Box 3)
  - Sermons “What Religion Means to Me” and “Religion in this New Day” (Both Updated and Delivered for Different Years between 1934-1946) (Box 3)
  - “Loneliness of Jesus, Loneliness of God”, 1934 March 25-1950 November 2 (Box 3)
  - “Simon of Cyrene”, 1944 July 9- 1946 July 28 (Box 3)
  - “Security in Worship, 1940 November 1 (Box 3)
  - “The Web of Life” Sermon for Mother’s Day, 1936 May 10 (Box 3)
  - “Mother and Her Flowers”, 1932 May 8 (Box 3)
  - Lenten Sermon on “Jesus’ Estimate of Man”, 1946 April 10 (Box 3)
  - “Jesus and Sin” for Lent 2, 1936 March 8 (Box 3)
  - “Worship’s Place in Student’s Lives” for Chapel Service, 1939 January 20 (Box 3)
  - “That They May Be One”, 1937 April 18 (Box 3)
  - “Paradoxes of the Spiritual Life”, 1938 November 3-6 (Box 3)
  - “The Art of Science”, 1933 October 22 (Box 3)
  - “Security”, 1933 February 26 (Box 3)
  - “Fundamentals of Experience: Saul-Paul”, 1935 February 17 (Box 3)
  - “Son of God… What is Man?”, 1933 May 7 (Box 3)
  - “The Inner Life of a Christian”, 1934 January 23 (Box 3)
  - “No One Cometh Unto the Father Save By Me” A Communion Sermon, 1934 February 4 (Box 3)
  - “Brotherhood: Who is My Brother?”, 1931 February 14 (Box 3)
  - Sermon Series on “Morals and the Christian” for Chapel, 1944 July 25-28 (Box 3)
  - “Perplexed, But Not Unto Despair”, 1932 October 23 (Box 3)
  - “The Larger Loyalty”, 1933 March 27 (Box 3)
  - “Under the Shadow of His Hand Hath He Hid Me”, 1936 February 9 (Box 3)
  - “God Loves You”, 1936 June 7 (Box 3)
  - “God-Today”, 1936 October 4 (Box 3)
  - “Place of Church; The Center for a Community”, 1936 October 22 (Box 3)
  - Sermon on Friends, Family, and Community of Church, 1932 May 15-1937 November 14 (Box 3)
  - “Thy Kingdom Come”, 1934 November 18 (Box 3)
  - “Finding God in the Common Place”, 1934 January 28 (Box 3)
  - “Word Became Flesh”, 1935 December 22 (Box 3)
  - “I Am Not Alone”, 1933 December 17 (Box 3)
  - “Supremacy of the Spiritual”, 1932 December 11 (Box 3)
  - “Strait is the Gate and Narrow the Way”, 1932 May 15 (Box 3)
  - “Jesus Looked the Church Over”, 1932 February 1 (Box 3)
  - “Without God-What?”, 1933 February 4 (Box 3)
- Speeches
  - Speech on Character Values, Circa 1945-1948 (Box 3)
  - Speech for Young People’s Conference (Akron, OH), 1937 November 27 (Box 3)
  - Speech for Parents and Teachers of Junior Children, 1942 January 21 (Box 3)
  - “Church as a Factor in Race Relations”, 1937 September 10 (Box 3)
  - “Resources for Times like These” Speech for University of Life, 1943 January 9 (Box 3)
  - “Go Preach” Speech for Graduates, 1938 May 29 (Box 3)
  - Speech on Need for Religious Education and on the Truly Abundant Life, 1938 October 16 (Box 3)
  - “Institution-Program-Community” Speech for International Institute, 1937 March 24 (Box 3)
  - “The Waiting World” Speech for Norwalk District Conference, 1937 October 25 (Box 3)
  - “Rethinking the Philosophy of Religious Education in Terms of Community, Life, and Needs”, 1940 November 10 (Box 3)
  - Objectives of Christian Education, Circa 1935-1943 (Box 3)
  - “Values in Teaching in the Church School” (Mt. Zion, Oberlin), 1946 January 8 (Box 3)
  - Church Presentation at COAN, 1934 October 28 (Box 3)
  - “Foundations for the Future Life”, 1933 April 9 (Box 3)
  - “Religion- Opiate or Stimulant?”, 1932 November 13 (Box 3)
  - “Technocracy” Speech for Bowery YMCA (New York City, NY), 1932 January 22 (Box 3)
  - “Racial Attitudes in Children” for Lincoln Forum, 1933 February 15 (Box 3)
  - “A Minister Looks at Birth”, 1935 February 27 (Box 3)
  - Speech for Director of Boys and Girls Work at Union Settlement Neighborhood House, 1935 February 2 (Box 3)
  - Speech on “Missions Today” for Epworth League Brooklyn, 1932 February 16 (Box 3)
  - “Home Missions”, 1936 October 10,16 (Box 3)
  - Speeches for Parents Forum, “Children’s Idea of God” and “Be Good”, 1935 May 23, 1941 November 15 (Box 3)
  - Speech on American Youth to a Forum for Parents, 1935 July 25 (Box 3)
  - Speech/Info and Materials, Speech along with Info and Materials for the Epworth League’s Jamesport Institute 1935, 1935 August 25- September 2 (Box 3)
  - Speech on Christian Education and the Church School in the Past World War., 1944 December 7-1945 May 15 (Box 3)
  - “Religion in a Community, 1942 September 13 (Box 3)
  - “Christian Citizenship and the Home”, 1930 October 30 (Box 3)
- Communion Liturgy
  - Communion Meditation, Circa 1933-1937 (Box 4)
  - Various Communion Liturgies, Circa 1936-1942 (Box 4)
  - “Grounding our Faith” Communion Liturgy, 1937 May 2 (Box 4)
  - “Abide in Me”, 1932 June 5 (Box 4)
  - “What is Man’s Worth? More than Sheep” A Communion Sermon, 1935 December 1 (Box 4)
  - “In the Name of the Lord” (A Communion Liturgy), 1934 May 6 (Box 4)
  - “In Touch with God” A Communion Sermon, 1932 April 3 (Box 4)
  - “Christ Liveth in Me” A New Years Sermon for Communion, 1933 January 6 (Box 4)
- Liturgies
  - Liturgy for Sunday Service Around the Text of Revelation 3:14-22, Circa 1932-1936 (Box 4)
  - Materials for Advent Liturgies and Homilies, Circa 1938 (Box 4)
- Bible Studies
  - “The Lost Art of Jesus”, 1932 January 8 (Box 4)
  - Bible Study for Church of All Nations, 1933 December 10 (Box 4)
- Lessons/Education Series
  - Series on Madonna and Art, 1939 December 13-16 (Box 4)
  - “What is the Christian Child?”, Circa 1932 (Box 4)
  - “Protestantism and Catholicism: A Comparison”, 1934 April 22 (Box 4)
  - “A Little Child in Their Midst: A Study on our Movies”, 1934 October 21 (Box 4)
  - Adult Education Series on New Testament, 1946 July 15, 1946 September 15 (Box 4)
- Broadcast Sermons/Devotionals
  - Sermons for Radio Broadcasts on WINS and WJZ Stations, 1934 March 31, 1937 June 7 (Box 4)
  - Lenten Sermon for WINS Radio Station, 1934 March 31 (Box 4)
  - Morning Devotionals for WJZ Station, 1935 December 19 (Box 4)
- Info, Materials, Notes
  - Notes, Materials and Notes on Christian Education for Children, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 4)
  - Notes, Speeches, and Homilies on Improving Race Relations and Lessening Hatred, Circa 1945-1946 (Box 4)
  - Notes, Notes for Sermon, “The Mind of Christ” for Church Retreat, 1940 May 6 (Box 4)
  - Notes, Notes for Teachers Group, 1941 March 13 (Box 4)
  - Notes, Notes and Materials for Sermon at Willis Avenue Church (Methodist Episcopal), Circa 1934-1941 (Box 4)
  - Notes, Notes on “Covenant Religion” Sermon, 1942 March 18 (Box 4)
  - Funeral Service, Memorial Service for Edward H. Foote, 1933 October 28 (Box 4)
  - Info/Materials, Info and Materials for Child Labor Sunday, 1932 January 29 (Box 4)
  - Speech/Sermon/Homily/Info/Materials, Various Sermons and Speeches for Special Occasions (Ordinations, Leadership Conferences, Family Forums, Baccalaureate Addresses, etc.) (Box 4)